Finding aid for Charles A. Sink Papers, 1900-1996
Bentley Historical Library
Charles A. Sink Papers
1900-1996
Bentley Historical Library
Sink, Charles A. (Charles Albert), 1879-1972
8654 Aa 2; Ac
21 linear feet
1 oversize folder
2.22 GB
Republican member of the state house and the state senate; president of the University Musical Society. Legislative and campaign files, 1919-1935, detailing his election campaigns, his activities within the legislature, and his various responsibilities as a member of the Republican State Central Committee; general correspondence files, 1922-1960, largely pertaining to his work with the University Musical Society and other civic activities; topical files; family history and memoirs; diaries and appointment books; papers of wife Alva Gordon Sink; and visual materials.
The collection was the gift of Charles A. Sink and his wife Alva Gordon Sink (donor no. 541 ) and came to the library in multiple accessions.
The collection is open to research.
The collection contains audio tapes from which digital copies have been made. Source tapes are for staff use only. Audio files are only available in the Bentley Historical Library reading room on designated Bentley Library computers.
Charles A. Sink was born July 4, 1879, in Westernville, NY in Oneida County, and attended high school in Churchville, NY He received a bachelor of arts degree from the University of Michigan in 1904. That same year, he began his long association with the University Musical Society, serving first as secretary (1904-07), executive manager (1907-27), and then president (1927-68). In addition, Sink was secretary and business manager of the University of Michigan School of Music (1904-27), then its president (1927-40).
Sink was also politically active. He served in both the state house and senate. He was a Republican member of the Michigan House of Representatives (1919-20 and 1925-26) and the Michigan Senate (1921-22, 1927-28, 1929-1930). In the legislature, Sink was chairman of the committees on education in both the Senate and House. Here he sponsored legislation affecting the state educational system and institutions. Sink was also a candidate in the 1932 primary for the office of lieutenant governor. Prior to this he was a member of the Republican State Central Committee (1928-32).
Throughout his life, Sink was involved in a variety of community and philanthropic activities. He died December 17, 1972.
The collection has been arranged into the following series: Legislative and Campaign Files; General Correspondence; Chronological Correspondence; Topical File; Clippings; Family History; Alva Gordon Sink papers; Charles and Alva Gordon Sink diaries and appointment books; Visual Materials; and Sound Recordings.
Banks and banking.; Elections -- Michigan -- 1926.; Elections -- Michigan -- 1928.; Elections -- Michigan -- 1932.; Music -- Michigan -- Ann Arbor.; Musicians -- Michigan -- Ann Arbor.; Philippines -- History -- 1898-1946.; Public schools -- Michigan -- Ann Arbor.; Roads -- Michigan.; Voyages and travels.; Aged persons -- Michigan -- Ann Arbor.; Agriculture -- Michigan.; Birthday parties -- Michigan -- Ann Arbor.; Children.; Capitols -- Michigan -- Lansing.; Dwellings -- Michigan -- Holly.; Eating and drinking.; Families.; Farms.; Funeral rites and ceremonies.; Holly (Mich.) -- Dwellings.; Lansing (Mich.) -- Capitols.; Manners & customs -- 1911-1920.; Musicians.; Ocean liners.; Passengers.; Singing -- Michigan -- Ann Arbor.; Travel.; Diaries.; Photographs.; Sound recordings.; Videotapes.; Ann Arbor Rotary Club.; Eastern Michigan University.; First Congregational Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Kelsey, Francis W. (Francis Willey), 1858-; Michigan Historical Commission.; Michigan. Legislature. House of Representatives.; Michigan. Legislature. Senate.; Michigan. Teachers' Retirement Fund Commission.; Michigan. Washington Bicentennial Commission.; National Association of Concert Managers.; Republican Party (Mich.); Sink, Alva Joanna Gordon.; Sink, Charles A. (Charles Albert), 1879-1972.; Starr Commonwealth for Boys.; University of Michigan -- Finance.; University of Michigan -- Choral organizations.; University of Michigan -- Orchestras.; University of Michigan. School of Music.; University of Michigan. University Musical Society.; Acacia Fraternity.; Alumnae House (University of Michigan); American National Red Cross.; Ann Arbor (Mich.). Common Council.; Ann Arbor May Festival.; Baird Carillon (University of Michigan); Beta Theta Pi. Lambda Chapter (University of Michigan); Bonisteel, Roscoe O. (Roscoe Osmond), 1888-; Burton, Marion Le Roy, 1874-1925.; Burton Tower (University of Michigan); Crisler, H. O. (Herbert Orin), 1899-1982.; Gordon family.; Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962.; Michigan. Legislature. House of Representatives.; Michigan. Legislature. Senate.; Michigan Life Insurance Company.; Ormandy, Eugene, 1899-1985.; Republican Party (Mich.); Sink, Alva Joanna Gordon.; Sink, Charles A. (Charles Albert), 1879-1972.; Sink family.; United States. Army.; University of Michigan -- Alumni and alumnae.; University of Michigan. Choral Union.; University of Michigan. College of Literature, Science, and the Arts. Class of 1923.; University of Michigan. University Musical Society.; Bates, Henry Moore, 1869-1949.; Beal, Junius E. (Junius Emery), 1860-1942.; Bonisteel, Roscoe O. (Roscoe Osmond), 1888-; Boyles, Emerson R., 1881-1960.; Brucker, Wilber Marion, 1894-1968.; Burton, Marion Le Roy, 1874-1925.; Burton, Nina M.; Cabot, Hugh, 1872-1945.; Clancy, Robert Henry, 1882-1962.; Clements, William L. (William Lawrence), 1861-1934.; Comstock, William Alfred, 1877-1949.; Cooley, Mortimer E. (Mortimer Elwyn), 1855-1944.; Copeland, Royal S. (Royal Samuel), 1868-1938.; Couzens, James, 1872-1936.; Dickinson, Luren Dudley, 1859-1943.; Fitzgerald, Frank Dwight, 1885-1939.; Ford, Edsel, 1893-1943.; Gansser, Augustus H., 1872-; Green, Fred W. (Fred Warren), 1872-1936.; Groesbeck, Alexander J. (Alexander Joseph), 1873-1953.; Hudson, Grant Martin, 1868-1955.; Hutchins, Harry B. (Harry Burns), 1847-1930.; Inglis, J. Gall (James Gall), 1864-1939.; Lennon, Peter B., 1878-; Little, Clarence C. (Clarence Cook), 1888-; Lockwood, Albert Lewis, 1871-1933.; McKay, Frank D., 1883-; McNutt, Paul Vories, 1891-1951.; Malcolm, George A. (George Arthur), 1881-1961.; Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1880-1956.; Menuhin, Yehudi, 1916-; Michener, Earl C. (Earl Cory), 1876-1957.; Moore, Earl Vincent, 1890-1987.; Munn, John.; Murfin, James Orin, 1875-1940.; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), 1860-; Palmer, Milton R., 1878-; Person, Seymour Howe, 1879-1957.; Potter, William W., 1869-1940.; Price, Percival, 1901-1985.; Sawyer, Walter H. (Walter Hulme), 1861-1931.; Shute, Nevil, 1899-1960.; Sink, Alva Joanna Gordon.; Smith, Shirley Wheeler, 1875-1959.; Stanley, Albert A. (Albert Augustus), 1851-1932.; Stone, Ralph, 1868-1956.; Turner, William F.; Upjohn, James T.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Wiley, Merlin, 1875-; Woodruff, Roy Orchard, 1876-1953.
- Legislative and Campaign Files
  - 1919-1927 (Box 1)
  - 1927-1930 (Box 2)
  - 1929-1932 (Box 3)
  - 1932-1935 (Box 4)
- General Correspondence
  - A-Z, 1922-1923 (Box 4)
  - A-L, 1923-1924 (Box 4)
  - M-Z, 1923-1924 (Box 5)
  - 1924 (Box 5)
    (miscellaneous)
  - A-Z, 1925 (Box 5)
  - 1925-1927 (Box 5)
  - A-Z, 1926-1927 (Box 5)
  - A-Z, 1927-1928 (Box 6)
  - A-Z, 1928-1929 (Box 6)
  - A-Z, 1929-1930 (Box 6)
  - A-Z, 1930-1931 (Box 6)
  - A-Z, 1931-1932 (Box 6)
  - A-Z, 1932-1933 (Box 7)
  - A-Z, March 1934-January 1935 (Box 7)
  - A-Z, 1935 (Box 7)
  - A-Z, 1936 (Box 7)
  - A-Z, November 1936-1937 (Box 7)
  - A-Z, 1937 (Box 7)
  - A-Z, September 1937-February 1938 (Box 8)
  - A-Z, February-September 1938 (Box 8)
  - A-Z, September 1938-January 1939 (Box 8)
  - A-Z, January-September 1939 (Box 8)
  - A-Z, September 1939-February 1940 (Box 8)
  - A-O, February-July 1940 (Box 8)
  - P-Z, February-July 1940 (Box 9)
  - A-Z, July 1940-January 1941 (Box 9)
  - A-Z, January-July 1941 (Box 9)
  - A-Z, July-December 1941 (Box 9)
  - A-Z, January-August 1942 (Box 9)
  - A-Z, September-December 1942 (Box 10)
  - A-Z, January-April 1943 (Box 10)
  - A-Z, April-August 1943 (Box 10)
  - A-Z, August-December 1943 (Box 10)
  - A-Z, January-April 1944 (Box 10)
  - A-L, May-December 1944 (Box 10)
  - M-Z, May-December 1944 (Box 11)
  - January-August 1945 (Box 11)
    (chronological)
  - A-Z, September 1945-April 1946 (Box 11)
  - A-Z, May-November 1946 (Box 11)
  - A-Z, November 1946-April 1947 (Box 11)
  - A-Z, May-December 1947 (Box 11)
  - A-M, January-August 1948 (Box 11)
  - N-Z, January-August 1948 (Box 12)
  - A-Z, September-December 1948 (Box 12)
  - A-Z, January-May 1949 (Box 12)
  - A-Z, June-December 1949 (Box 12)
  - A-Z, January-July 1950 (Box 12)
  - A-Z, August 1950-February 1951 (Box 12)
  - A-O, March-December 1951 (Box 12)
  - P-Z, March-December 1951 (Box 13)
  - A-Z, January-October 1952 (Box 13)
  - A-Z, November 1952-August 1953 (Box 13)
  - A-Z, September 1953-August 1954 (Box 13)
  - A-Z, September 1954-October 1955 (Box 13)
  - A-Z, October 1955-July 1956 (Box 13)
  - A-Z, August 1956-February 1957 (Box 13)
  - A-Z, March 1957-1960 (Box 14)
- Chronological correspondence (later accession)
  - Undated, 1900-1972; 16 folders (Box 14)
- Topical File
  - Acacia Fraternity (Box 14)
  - American Red Cross, Washtenaw County Chapter, 1943-1954 (Box 14)
  - Awards, appointments and honors (Box 14)
    (see also oversize folder Ac)
  - Biographical (Box 14)
  - Bonisink Saga (Box 14)
  - Christmas cards (Box 14)
  - Class notebooks, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Huguenot Society of Michigan, 1937-1945 (Box 15)
  - Lieutenant Governor campaign, 1932; 3 folders (Box 15)
  - "Memory book", 1934-1940; 6 folders (Box 15)
    (requests for autographed copies of books from writers, musicians, and other public figures)
  - Miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 15)
  - National Association of Concert Mangers, 1949-1955; 8 folders (Box 15)
  - Rotary Club (Box 15)
  - Scrapbook, ca., 1919-1925; 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Shute, Nevil (Norway) (Box 16)
  - Sink, Dr. Emory W. (Box 16)
  - Sink, Loren A. (Box 16)
  - Speeches (Box 16)
  - Teachers Retirement Fund, 1930-1931; 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Travels (Box 16)
  - Villicus, Fritz (Box 16)
  - World War I, war effort activities (Box 16)
  - Ypsi-Ann Land Company, 1925-1929 (Box 16)
- Clippings
  - Undated, 1920-1972; 29 folders (Box 16)
- Family history
  - "A bit of family history and a few reminiscences" (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous family materials (Box 17)
- Alva Gordon Sink
  - Correspondence
    - Personal (Box 18)
    - Condolences on death of her husband (Box 18)
  - Topical File
    - Alumni activities (Box 18)
    - Alva Gordon Sink Alumnae Club (Box 18)
    - Biographical materials (Box 18)
    - Community activities (Box 18)
    - Hospitality (Box 18)
    - Johnson, Thor (about), 1975 (Box 18)
    - Philanthropies (Box 18)
    - Republican Party Platform Planning Committee (Box 18)
    - University of Michigan Emeritus Club (Box 18)
  - Clippings, 1923-1959; 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Guest books, 8 volumes (Box 18)
- Charles and Alva Gordon Sink
  - Diaries and appointment books (Box 19)
  - Diaries and appointment books (Box 20)
    (continued)
- Visual Materials
  - Photographs
    - Topical
      - Acacia Fraternity and Beta Theta Pi (Box 21)
      - Alumnae House (Box 21)
      - Ann Arbor City Council, 1917 (Box 21)
      - Awards and dedication ceremonies (Box 21)
      - Baird Carillon (Box 21)
      - Burton family (including Marion L. Burton) (Box 21)
      - Burton (Marion) funeral (Box 21)
      - Friends (Box 21)
      - Gordon family home, Holly, Michigan (Box 21)
      - May Festival (Box 21)
        (in over size folder Ac)
      - Michigan Capitol Building; members of Michigan legislature; Michigan House and Senate Club (Box 21)
      - Michigan Life Insurance Company (Box 21)
      - Musicians (including Fritz Kreisler and Fritz Crisler) (Box 21)
      - Ormandy, Eugene (receiving honorary degree) (Box 21)
    - Sink, Alva Gordon
      - Informal (Box 21)
      - Photograph album, 1910s (Box 21)
    - Sink, Charles and Alva
      - Official occasions (Box 21)
      - With musicians (Box 21)
      - Travels and vacations (Box 21)
      - Informal poses together (Box 21)
    - Sink family (include agricultural scene) (Box 21)
    - Portraits inscribed to Sink, 5 folders (Box 21)
  - Videotapes
    - Alva Gordon Sink 100th birthday celebration, 1995 (Box 21)
    - Alva Gordon Sink 101st birthday celebration, 1996 (Box 21)
- Sound recordings
  - Sound recordings
    [Access to digital audio files currently restricted to Bentley Library reading room]
    - Rotary luncheon honoring Charles A. Sink, 1966 July 20; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 in. reel; 3 3/4 ips (Box 21)
      - [Part 1], [8654-SR-1-1]; (Recording of Rotary luncheon honoring Charles A. Sink. Tape comes with 3 sheet program and transcription of event.)
  - Audio Cassettes
    - Oral interview with Alva Gordon Sink, circa 1970s; 3 audiocassettes (Box 21)
      (includes unedited transcript of the recordings)
    - Oral interview with Alva Gordon Sink, June 1994; 2 audiocassettes (with duplicate copies) (Box 21)